

WESLEY JONES

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER \$\cup +1 (585) 831-4961

• DETAILS •

+1 (585) 831-4961 waj194@gmail.com

LINKS

Portfolio

GitHub

Drupal.org

LinkedIn

SKILLS

Drupal

Project Lead

Node.js

LAMP Stack

Varnish/CDN

CI Integration

Docker and Vagrant

Image Optimization

Responsive Web Design

Personalization

LANGUAGES

English

Spanish

Mandarin Chinese

Arabic

American Sign Language

PROFILE

Accomplished Web Software Engineer specializing in Drupal, with a decade of experience planning, building and maintaining websites.

Objective: To work remotely for a highly collaborative, process oriented, and friendly company, and use my skills to lead projects for enterprise clients, delivering digital experiences built in Drupal, Node.js, and beyond.

■ EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Senior Software Engineer / Technical Architect at Third and Grove, Boston, MA (remote) February 2015 — February 2022

Developed Drupal sites for enterprise clients. Collaborated with fully distributed team using Slack, Zoom, and Jira, and developer tools Docker, GitHub, Drush, Travis Cl, Node.js, Acquia Cloud, Pantheon, and AWS.

As Technical Architect, worked closely with the project manager and client on discovery, technical architecture, estimation, and sprint planning. Managed the build team, performed code reviews and deployments.

Freelance Web Developer at Wes Jones (self), Rochester, NY

December 2011 — Present

Developed websites for local businesses and real estate agencies in the Rochester, NY area. Drupal consultant for Eastman Museum Technicolor100 project. Drupal consultant for Boston Museum of Science - contributed to main website redesign initiative and converted Wordpress microsites to Drupal 7. Member of the Toptal freelance network.

SEO Specialist / Web Developer at Accelerate Media, Inc, Rochester, NY

February 2014 — February 2015

Performed SEO audits and keyword research, managed Google AdWords PPC campaigns, and implemented A/B tests. Developed client projects with Wordpress and Yii Framework, managed projects and QA for build team.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Mathematics and Computer Information Systems, SUNY Brockport May 2009

3.85 GPA. President's List with Honors, Brockport Math and Computer Science Scholar. Student representative on the Computer Science Curriculum Committee. Student Web Developer.

★ CERTIFICATIONS

Acquia Certified Developer - Drupal 7

Acquia Certified Back End Specialist - Drupal 9

Acquia Personalization Pro